csir.co.za 2018-10-11

# CSIR Website Privacy Notice | CSIR

**This copy is available in[Sepedi](https://www.csir.co.za/documents/csirprivacynoticesepedipdf) and [isiZulu](https://www.csir.co.za/documents/csirprivacynoticeisizulupdf)**

The CSIR cares about your personal information and we therefore provide you (the user of this website) with this notice so that you may make an informed decision about whether you would like to use the website or not.

**Please note that by using this website you consent to this Privacy Notice.   If you do not consent to this Privacy Notice you must stop using this website immediately.**

**What personal information do we collect?**

When you use this website, the CSIR collects the following personal information automatically (this will always be recorded without you having to do anything):

  * Your IP address, browser and operating system information;
  * The date and time you accessed the website;
  * Your geographic location The pages you view while using the website;
  * Any search terms you use when using the website’s search functionality.

In addition, we collect any personal information that you voluntarily provide to the CSIR.  For example, by submitting a CV or subscribing to a newsletter.

**What do we do with it?**

The personal information we collect automatically is to help the CSIR improve the functionality and content of its website.

The information we collect that you provide voluntarily is to provide you with a service, or facilitate a function, where your personal information is required to provide the service or fulfil the function.

**Who do we share it with?**

We share the personal information you provide voluntarily and the personal information we collect automatically differently.

Personal information provided voluntarily:

We do not share this personal information with third parties unless we have a justifiable reason to do so.  Typically, the third parties who will have access to your personal information are the contracted parties who assist us with the development of the website IT maintenance and related matters

In certain circumstances we may be forced by law to share your personal information, for example, when served with a court order or other valid request from a lawful authority.

In other circumstances we may share personal information that has been anonymised and it will not be possible to link the information to a specific individual.

Personal information collected automatically:

Some of the personal information that is collected automatically is collected by third parties whose technology we use to provide website functionality and acquire website analytics information.  The table below lists these third parties, where they are located, details on opting out of their personal information collection, and if available, their contact details for privacy queries.

In addition, if you make use of the social media sharing buttons on the website, your information will be automatically collected by the social media company that you use to share content (see the “Social Media Platforms and External Links” section below).

**How do we collect your personal information?**

With regard to the personal information we collect, we make use of a number of technologies that collect personal information automatically:

**Cookies:   **Cookies are small files that are saved onto your computer which track, save and store information about how you use this website.  In some instances, these cookies are needed for the website to function – you can disable them in your browser but this may interfere with the proper functioning of the website.

**Google analytics:**  This is tracking software from Google which we use to monitor how users interact with the website in order for us to improve its functionality and content. 

**Web-server software:** Web-server software delivers web-pages to your browser.  The web-server software will automatically collect your IP address whenever you connect to the website.

**YouTube:** This is software used to display videos.  We do not collect personal information from you by placing these videos on our site or through you viewing them, but Google Inc. (which owns YouTube) collects personal information when videos are placed on webpages.

**AddToAny:** This is software that is used to place social media buttons on our website which allows you to share content on our website through social media.  We do not collect personal information by placing these buttons on our site, but the AddToAny company does.

**Social media platforms and external links**

This website may make use of social media platforms such as Facebook or LinkedIn.  Whenever you make use of any such platforms on this website please note that any personal information you share on these platforms is subject to their privacy policies and not the CSIR’s.

This website may also contain links to external (non-CSIR) websites.  Whenever you click a link and are taken to an external website, note that your use of these websites is governed by their privacy policies and not the CSIR’s.

**Securing your information**

We take care to protect your personal information using information security safeguards, however, you should be aware that no safeguards are 100% effective all of the time and it is therefore possible that your personal information may be accessed by unauthorised or unknown persons should these safeguards be defeated or fail.

**Changes to this Notice**

We may amend this privacy notice at any time.  All amendments shall be posted on this website. Unless we state otherwise, the current version will replace all previous versions of this notice.  It is your responsibility to check for changes each time you visit the website.

**How to contact us:**

**Privacy Office**

**Building 3B**

**Physical Address**

Meiring Naudé Road

Brummeria

Pretoria

South Africa  

**Postal Address**

**Privacy Office**

**Building 3B**

PO Box 395

Pretoria 0001

South Africa

**Telephone Number**

012-841 3267
